Java Developer

Vijay Tambe

Croydon, CR0 6PQ | +44-7467740945 | vijaydt89@gmail.com

Personal Statement

I am a versatile Java Developer with over 8 years of experience in software development and passion to learn and explore new technologies. I have extensive experience in building web applications, web services, RESTFul API, and working on integration projects. I have worked in both Waterfall and Agile development environment. My core technical skills are Java, Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, React, JavaScript, and MySQL.

Technical Skills

Java Technologies : Core Java, Java EE, JPA, Streams, Lambdas, Collections

Java Frameworks : Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JUnit, Mockito, Liferay, Oracle ATG, Swagger

Web Technologies : React, JavaScript, NodeJs, JQuery, HTML, CSS

Databases : MySQL, PostgreSQL, H2

Template Engines : JSP, Thymeleaf

IDE : Eclipse, IntelliJ, VS CodeDevOps : Docker, CI/CD, Jenkins, AWSNoSQL : Solr, Oracle Endeca, MongoDB

Version Control : Git, SVN

Build automation: Maven, Gradle

Libraries : POI, Apache Commons, HttpComponent, XDocReport, Liquibase, Lombok,

Gson, Jackson, Snake YAML, Dom4j, SLF4j

WebServices : REST, MicroServices

Agile Development : Agile, Scrum, Kanban, BDD, TDD

Professional Experience

Java Developer, Avenir Digital Ltd, May 2017 to Present

Project Name: CNHI – enterprise application for CNHI dealers

Brief description: This is an enterprise application built for CNHI dealers. CNHI dealers use this application in their day to day business to maintain customer details, sales info, product catalog, check the sales report, store documents and also to send promotions. This is a multilingual application used across Europe. It handles 2,000 dealers, a hundred thousand customer details and around the same amount of products.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in requirement gathering, user story design, and implementation.
- Designed and developed various Spring MVC portlet to render the contents on-page.
- Designed and developed UI with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery.
- Involved in database design and responsible to create database objects like stored procedures, packages, and functions.
- Added Hibernate entities, mappings, transaction management, extensively used criteria query and named query.
- Used Agile methodology of software development.
- Worked in CI/CD environment.
- Developed JMS components to trigger the tasks in the background.
- Developed feature using apache POI to create and upload the XLS file with thousands of records.

- Used AJAX to refresh parts of pages.
- Created new Freemarker templates and added new macros.
- Written unit test cases using JUnit and Mockito
- Extensively worked with Streams, Lambdas and Functional Interfaces.
- Extended Liferay OOTB APIs to add custom features.
- Performed code reviews and build configurations using Gradle,
- Involved in performance tuning of application, investigated the heap dump of application.
- Completed POC's for client requirement using Liferay features.

Project Name: Savtrix – document migration system

Brief description: This is a document and content migration system, the main aim of this system is to migrate thousands of millions of documents and contents from one system to another for example Share Point to Salesforce. This product is still in development.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in requirement gathering, user story design, and implementation.
- Responsible to create the base setup for RESTFul service using Spring Boot.
- Configured Spring boot with PostgreSQL and Elastic Search.
- Configured Spring Boot service with swagger using definition first approach.
- Implemented a number of REST APIs endpoints.
- Extensive use of Spring JPA to create repositories, entities also added a number of custom functions to perform operations on the database.
- Involved in React development to create an admin dashboard for system. Implemented a number of components using Class as well as Functions.
- Used Fetch to request Spring Boot service, extensively used promises to complete the ajax operations.
- Written unit test cases using JUnit and Mockito.
- Added number of integration unit test cases for Spring Boot service.
- Created Kafka agents to read contents from the Liferay repository and send message over Kafka.
- Created Kafka agents to read messages from Kafka and write them into target Liferay repository.
- Build RESTFul web services using JAX-RS API.
- Build client to consume SOAP services of Liferay.
- Designed database schema for many tables.
- Added new modules, dependencies, and plugins to Maven.

Project Name: DIY.com – online store of B&O

Brief description: DIY.com is an online store of DIY and home improvement retail company B&Q.

Responsibilities:

- Meetings with stakeholders to improve site search.
- Worked in the Agile methodology.
- Worked in CI/CD environment.
- Implemented auto-suggestion feature for site.
- Added unit test cases using JUnit and Mockito
- Involved in performance tuning of the Endeca service.
- Completed Oracle Endeca migration POC from version 3 to version 11.
- Added Python scripts to automate Endeca-service related process.
- Added various cartridges and components to implement the facet search feature.
- Integration of Bazzarvoice service to fetch product ratings.
- Tried to achieve real-time data indexing.
- Indexed data from multiple data sources.
- Also worked in Pair programming

Technical Stack: Java EE, Spring, Spring Boot, Liferay, Kafka, Restful API, Swagger, Oracle DB, PostgreSQL, Hibernate, EJB, JavaScript, JQuery, React, Maven, Gradle, POI, Liquibase, Apache Tomcat, JBoss, JMS, JUnit, Mockito

Sr. Associate L1, Facet Commerce Pvt Ltd, April 2016 to May 2017

Project Name: Siemens – B2B platform

Brief description: Siemens is a well-known German company. This project was a migration project the legacy B2B platform to the new platform with the latest technologies in the market. It was implemented with headless architecture and microservices. This was a multilingual project, it was handling hundreds of thousands of products and document manuals.

Responsibilities:

- Won performer of the month award.
- Involved in requirement gathering, design and user story creation.
- Implemented mega navigation, facet search, free text search of website.
- Mentored two Junior developers, guiding them, preparing them.
- Created microservice to handle search related features of site.
- Integrated web service with web application that was built using handlebar templates.
- Performed code reviews.
- Written unit test cases using the Spock framework.
- Extensive use of Java 8 features like Streams, Lambdas, Functional Interfaces.

Project Name: Price comparison engine

Brief description: This was a price comparison engine for India stores. It was handling products from hundreds of stores and thousands of products. It also handles offers, deals, and coupons from various stores. This project is still in development.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in requirement gathering, design and user story creation.
- Built microservices using Spring Boot to perform various operations like real-time product pricing, handling offers, product search, user information.
- Implemented search features using Solr.
- Used template engine Thymeleaf to create UI of catalog system with Spring.
- Used NoSQL database MongoDB to store, analyze, and aggregate the catalog from hundreds of stores.
- Used Apache Spark stream to perform operations with MongoDB
- Created a web service clients using HttpComponents to fetch data from stores.
- Written unit and integration testing using JUnit and Mockito.
- Created technical and design documents.
- Used Hibernate to create entities, mappings, repositories.

Technical Stack: Java EE, NodeJs, Oracle Endeca, ATG, Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Restful API, Solr, MongoDB, Shell script, Thymeleaf, MicroServices, Spock, JavaScript, React, HttpComponent, JUnit, Mockito, Apache Tomcat, JBoss

Sr. Software Engineer, TAIS Tech Ltd, May 2014 to March 2016

Brief description: Throughout tenure with TAIS Tech, I was involved in multiple projects, Toys R Us (UK and Poland region), Natural Partners, SARAX 11.1. All these are well known online stores.

- Added various spring Beans and controllers to implement new features and to add new pages.
- Extensively used JSP with JSTL as template engine and developed new pages.
- Involved in bug fixing using JavaScript, CSS, HTML.
- Managed association such as one-to-many, many-to-many, many-to-one.
- Written SQL, HQL, named queries and Criteria queries.
- Integration of Oracle ATG and Endeca.
- Debugging and troubleshooting the problems.
- Created Oracle Endeca cartridges.
- Developed custom cartridge handlers.
- Implemented property accessors for custom properties and dimensions.
- Implemented droplets to read and render the data.

- Implemented facet search, free text search, and auto-suggestion features.
- Responsible to mentor junior developers.
- Created and maintained the design and technical documentation.
- Involved in requirement gathering and design.
- Created and manipulated a number of shell scripts to automate the process.
- Used Experience Manager to configure new pages, thesaurus, synonyms and to add new rules.
- Involved in performance improvement activities.
- Involved in production deployment and support activities.

Technical Stack: Core Java, Java EE, JSP, Oracle Endeca, ATG, Shell script, Endeca Experience Manager, Jackson, Apache Commons, JUnit, Mockito, JBoss, Weblogic, Apache Ant, Maven, Javascript, CSS, JQuery

Endeca Developer, Amplifi Commerce, September 2013 to April 2014

Project name: Yankee Candle

Brief description: Yankee candle is a large scented candle producer and retailer in the USA. This project was to migrate their legacy online store to the new online store.

Responsibilities:

- Developed number of pages using JSP and JSTL.
- Used JUnit and Mockito to write unit test cases.
- Added number of java components to add the business logic.
- Wired number of components using the DI framework on Oracle ATG.
- Added AJAX calls to perform actions on-page.
- Using javascript to handle events of user actions.

Technical stack: Core Java, Java EE, JSP, Oracle Endeca, ATG, Shell script, Endeca Experience Manager, JUnit, Mockito, JBoss, Apache Ant, JavaScript

Software Engineer, Cybage Software Pvt Ltd, November 2011 to September 2013

Project name: US Auto Parts

Project description: US Auto Parts is a leading online auto parts provider. This was a web service application to feed product data to US Auto Parts system.

Responsibilities:

- Worked on chain of responsibility design pattern.
- Involved in product release and support.
- Involved in bug fixing and maintenance of the system.
- Added new feature to the Spring Webservice.
- Integration of Oracle Endeca and Spring
- Used Apache Ant to package the Webservice.
- Used shell scripts and PHP scripts to copy, manipulate data and files.
- Design and create JSON response according to front-end pages.
- Use of OOPs concepts and other core java concepts like concurrency, inheritance, exception handling, collection, etc in development.

Technical stack: Core Java, Java EE, JSP, Spring, Webservices, Oracle Endeca, Shell script, PHP scripting, JUnit, Mockito, Apache Ant, Apache Tomcat

Education

Degree and Year	Institute	University/Board	Division
PG-DAC (Diploma in Advance Computing) (2011)	Sunbeam Institute of Information Technology (Pune)	C-DAC ACTS	A+
B.E. (Computer Engineering) (2010)	Rajendra Mane College of Eng & Tech, Devrukh (Ratnagiri)	University of Mumbai	I